RG 002:025, Commission to Study Legislation to Limit the Conduct of Business in Connecticut by Subsidiaries of Bank Holding Companies
Connecticut State Library
Bank Holding Companies Study Commission records
1979-1982
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Commission to Study Legislation to Limit the Conduct of Business in Connecticut by Subsidiaries of Bank Holding Companies
.75 cubic feet
The Commission was established by Public Act 79-563 to inquire into, study and report on the desirability of legislation to limit the extent to which a bank holding company, whether organized under the laws of Connecticut or any other state, may maintain an office or conduct any business in Connecticut through a subsidiary of such holding company.
RG002_025_BANKHOLD
1984-030
Historical Note
The Commission was established by Public Act 79-563 to inquire into, study and report on the desirability of legislation to limit the extent to which a bank holding company, whether organized under the laws of Connecticut or any other state, may maintain an office or conduct any business in Connecticut through a subsidiary of such holding company. The Commission, also known as the Hebb Commisson after its chairman, attorney Edwin Gordon Hebb, Jr. of Hartford, held its first organizational meeting on November 1, 1979. The Commission disbanded in 1983.
Scope and Content
Includes a briefing book, meeting notices, minutes, report of the Commission, responses to request for information, tesimonies, and a transcript.
Related Material
, Connecticut State Library.
, Connecticut State Library.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Banks and banking -- Government policy -- Connecticut; Bank holding companies -- Connecticut; Banking law -- Connecticut; Connecticut. Commission to Study Legislation to Limit the Conduct of Business in Connecticut by Subsidiaries of Bank Holding Companies -- Records and correspondence
Document Types:
Agendas (administrative records); Clippings (informatin artifacts); Correspondence; Minutes (administrative records); Reports; Testimonies; Transcripts
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1979-1982
  - Agenda, 1981 February 27 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Briefing book, 1979 March - May (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Joint favorable reports, 1980 February - March (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - List of lobbyists, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Meeting notices, 1979 October - 1980 February (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Memorandum, 1981 November 12 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1979 November - 1980 January, 1982 November 9 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - News clippings, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Report of Commission, 1980 February 5 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Includes a copy of the minority report.
    Copies of reports dated 1982 and 1983 not included in these records are available at and
  - Reports from other sources, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Responses to request for information, 1979 November - 1980 January (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Responses to request for information - Connecticut Bankers Association, 1980 January 23 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    A copy is available at
  - Responses to request for information - Citicorp, 1980 January 23 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - State laws (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Testimonies, 1979 December - 1980 March, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Transcript, 1979 December 6 (Box 2, Folder 3)